The fate of an empire. The descent of man.
Titus is a drama, history film directed by Julie Taymor.
Titus Andronicus returns from the wars and sees his sons
and daughters taken from him, one by one.
Shakespeare's goriest and earliest tragedy.
Titus Andronicus, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Tamora, played by Jessica Lange.
Chiron, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Demetrius, played by Matthew Rhys.
Aaron, played by Harry Lennix.
Lucius, played by Angus Macfadyen.
Titus is a 1999 epic surrealist historical drama film written, co-produced, and directed by Julie Taymor
in her feature directorial debut, based on William Shakespeare's tragedy Titus Andronicus.
A co-production between Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States, the film stars Anthony Hopkins in the title role of
Titus Andronicus, the Roman army general, chronicling his downfall following a victorious return from war.
It was produced by Overseas Filmgroup and Clear Blue Sky
Productions and released by Fox Searchlight Pictures.
The film received mixed-to-positive reviews from critics and was a box-office bomb,
grossing approximately $2.9 million worldwide against a budget of $18 million.
At the 72nd Academy Awards, it received a
nomination for the Best Costume Design.
The film explores themes of rome, italy, loss of loved
one, repayment, battle for power, commander.
The tone is emotional.